lain Maitland

Fullstack Developer



About

13512 Gable Street

Detroit Michigan MI 48212 US

(737) 226-3943

iainmaitland.com

imaitland

y iain_maitland

Web Development

Professional

React Rust Typescript Javascript NodeJS/Deno GraphQL

MySql/NoSql/Postgres

DevOps

Professional

AWS Docker Git

Languages

English (Native speaker)

Interests

Art

Photography Poetry Writing

Summary

lain has a degree from the University of Cambridge in Law and History of Art and 5 years experience as a frontend and full-stack web developer. Before going freelance, he worked as an early employee for Steem, building user-facing apps and backend micro-services, with React, Typescript, and NodeJS on their blockchain as it scaled to 1M+ users. He has been learning Rust more recently, using it to make a static site generator, a key-value database, and working on an email subscription service. He is excited by any opportunity to use Rust's powerful features in production, particularly when it can complement his experience with Typescript, Javascript, and React.

Experience

Freelance 05/2020 - Present

Develop useful software for a variety of clients Fullstack developer

Working as a lead developer with a local and remote team of graphic and product designers to implement creative and b2b software briefs for a range of clients, including General Motors.

- https://hobbes.work a portfolio site for a UI/UX studio using a modern Jamstack, a customized headless CMS, and a React/Typescript frontend
- https://means.tv a media streaming platform with subscription features
- https://psilabs.org laboratory process tracking software and web front end, so customers can track their samples and publicize test results.
- A custom CRM for General Motors in React and NodeJS used at Dealerships and special events nationwide.

Steemit.com

Developed applications for the Steem blockchain Fullstack Developer

Worked as part of a remote agile team with 3 other developers, to develop and scale open source blockchain software (https://github.com/steemit) used by millions of users and processing millions of dollars in cryptocurrency transactions.

- Built the most popular frontend (React/Typescript) for the Steem blockchain, including authorization, market trading, and cryptocurrency wallet features
- https://steemit.com A reddit clone written in React, scaling from a few thousand to millions of users internationally
- https://signup.steemit.com/ User creation service or 'faucet,' onboarded more than a million new users
- https://wallet.steemit.com Feature-rich cryptocurrency wallet including trading, exchange and withdrawal

Quikly 05/2017 - 03/2018

Developed an administration dashboard in React Frontend Developer

Worked as lead React developer as part of an agile team on b2b dashboard software.

- Build out a GraphQL api in Ruby-on-rails to drive the react frontend
- Advocate for Typescript adoption within the company

Penske Media Corporation

01/2016 - 05/2017

03/2018 - 05/2020

Developed CMSs and frontends for magazines like rollingstone.com and variety.com Frontend Developer

Worked as part of an agile team with 2 other developers, developed CMS backends in Contentful, Wordpress and Drupal and frontends in React

Lead pivot from traditional CMS instances to a headless model

Education